Douglas R. Applegate

New Palestine, IN | 317-432-4727 | doappleg@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/dougapplegate

Professional Summary

I am a versatile, collaborative, and strategic self-starter with vision who has proven success in moving company initiatives and client success to the next level. I have created highly effective post-sales teams and processes that drive customer lifetime value and improved customer satisfaction. I'm highly skilled at interpreting data and identifying business opportunities through that analysis, I've created relevant and intuitive content for sales and marketing purposes, and delivered results within various business environments. Over 10 years of having achieved award winning and consistent results through strategic planning, effective coaching and mentoring, client-first attitude, collaborative execution, creative problem solving and a relentless pursuit of personal growth

Additional areas of strength and technical skill include:

- Create and execute business analysis, budget planning, goals/targets programs, and employee engagement initiatives.
- Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C# and Python)
- SaaS Client Success and Account growth.
- Talent Recruitment strategy, sourcing and execution.

- Data Analysis and Forecasting (Excel and SQL).
- Customer Onboarding and Implementation (product and service).
- Project Management (Agile-Scrum methodology and Design/Update sprint collaboration)
- Startup Market Research, Pitch Decks, Exec Summaries, and User Research

From volunteerism to consultancy I have provided support and collaborative leadership to Fortune 500 and SMB companies, non-profits, tech startup's, or trade associations with a desire to win and do good for society.

Career Experience

COVID19 Sabbatical March 2020 - Current

Technical skill-up and Entrepreneurial exploration

Due to loss of employment caused by COVID19, I took the opportunity to explore my own business startup ideas and technical skillset. Here is a snapshot into my journey:

- **gAlpha Indy 5G:** in gener8tor's first **gAlpha Indy** cohort (May 2020). gAlpha Indy was a 5G focused startup ideation and creation program lasting 4 weeks. Out of that cohort came my idea of 1Fan, a fan engagement and experience app for sports and entertainment events and venues.
- **Leap Talent:** Leap Talent is an HR Tech and Candidate Video Marketing platform idea that I am currently building with a co-founder. Currently under development and in the early stages of building an MVP product for beta testing in early 2021.
- **The Mill Code School:** The Mill (a co-working space based in Bloomington, IN) partnered with gener8tor to provide a 10-week Software Development bootcamp where I learned web and software development skills such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C#, SQL and Python coding languages. I am currently building a portfolio of projects via the bootcamp and will graduate December 2020.

Eleven Fifty Academy Director, Industry Engagement

November 2019 - March 2020

Eleven Fifty Academy is a non-profit coding bootcamp and cybersecurity academy. My responsibilities include the following:

- Accelerated development of new and existing partner relations with technology employers throughout Indianapolis.
- Collaborated with 50+ employer partners to deliver EFA graduates and alumni for hire.
- Increased graduate recruitment and placement by 30% within 90 days.

- Produced employer skills focused projects that led to increased engagement from industry leaders across Indiana.
 - Successful projects included alumni engagement, student-employer interactions (i.e. mock interviews, career days, etc.), and creation of direct hiring pipelines with area employers hiring tech talent.
- Collaborated with the internal stakeholders (Admissions, Learning, and Marketing) on the Academy's to develop employer specific skill-up and training programs.
- Partnered with the Marketing team on content marketing for website blog, email campaigns, and webinars.

Defenders June 2019 - November 2019

Director, Customer Success and Retention

Led and managed two teams (total of 23 ee's) within the Defenders Customer Experience Call Center (CEC) responsible for New Customer Retention and Escalated Complaint Management.

- Led improved team performance, increased awareness and communication for Executive Leadership, and created better efficiency for cross-departmental communication (sales, customer service, and technical support).
- Forged a higher level of communication and consistency within a fast-paced call center environment for the partnership of ADT's corporate escalation management teams.
- Utilized data analysis and metric measurement via Microsoft SharePoint and BI platforms often collaborating with the Defenders BI and Call Center management teams.
- Optimized utilization and interaction with reputation management platforms such as ADT corporate, BBB, Glassdoor, and TrustPilot.
- Led both teams to reach Visionary (100%+ to goal) level performance in company based OKRs and WIG's.

WorkHere May 2018 - April 2019

Vice President of Client Success & Business Development

WorkHere is an award-winning Indianapolis based HR Tech/SaaS startup providing hyper-local recruitment marketing services that deliver talent for local employers. My impact included:

- Created a highly effective post-sales organization that drove \$15K MRR customer lifetime value and improved client satisfaction and acted as customer facing product expert.
- Optimized customer onboarding and training, product implementation, contract negotiations, account billing and retention, and all related customer service and technical support issues.
- Developed sales strategy and hunted new B2B clientele in retail, beauty, logistics, and automotive industries to grow net new customers by 50% YOY.
- Provide analysis and advice to customers on advertising and branding strategies, geofencing and sourcing campaign structure and outcomes.
- Collaborated with Marketing and Technical Writing teams on successful design and update sprints content marketing, social media strategy, email campaigns, podcasts, webinars, and account-based marketing content for Sales and Client Success purposes.
- Successfully reduced customer churn by 30% YOY and improved Net Revenue by \$40K
- Company pivoted focus and direction that eliminated the need for a Client Success role.

Kelly Services Inc. April 2015- Feb 2018

Sr. Business Operations Leader

Responsibilities and success pertain to the development, execution, and management of territory related sales and recruitment growth, operational excellence, leadership, and overall financial performance in the Indianapolis Territory.

- Led and managed Indy area branch sales, account management and recruiting performance, enabling the Indy teams to meet or exceed financial and operational goals.
- Orchestrated sales and fulfillment results of 103%, 110%, and 130% YOY growth in consecutive years (top line sales, gross profit and net profit).
- Developed and effectively trained branch sales teams which contributed to Kelly's annual revenue growth
 in Indianapolis. This training program also included creating an employee engagement and culture
 improvement initiative.

- Recruited, Interviewed and Hired additional contract and full-time employees to accommodate and address market growth.

Integrity Staffing Solutions

February 2014 - February

2015

Sr. Territory Business Manager

Responsible for the establishment, management, and growth of Integrity's first commercial staffing services branch in Indianapolis.

- Started at zero (0) billable hours and successfully grew to over 1500 billable hours within 6 months.
- Grew team of one to 3 due to increased business within the first 6 months.
- Established talent pipeline via recruitment and sourcing efforts driving both placement and sales success.

Angie's List

January 2013 - December

2013

Advertising Account Manager

Responsible for the management, retention and increased investment levels for first year advertising accounts.

- Managed over 250+ clients in the service industry with annual revenue of \$2 million.
- Achieved an average monthly client renewal performance of 106% to goal.
- Achieved average CV value upselling of 35% above previous contract value.

Key Benefit Administrators

November 2011 - December 2012

Business Development Executive - Wellness

- Successfully developed new marketing and sales content and proposals, gained new market share by 20%
- Established and grew sales pipeline for newly created wellness division via inside/outside sales activities toward prospective partners and clients.
- Licensed Insurance Broker in Health and Life with IN, IL, KY, MI, OH, NC, SC, GA, WI, VA, MO, and FL

Maxim Healthcare Services

September 2006 – November 2011

Regional Account Executive - Wellness (2010-11) Account Manager (2008-10)

Healthcare Staffing and Homecare Recruiter (2006-08)

Education and Volunteering

Indiana University | Bachelor of Arts - Communication Studies

Minor Certificate in Music

- Speech Club, Rec Sports leagues, founding member and collaborator of Jag Radio (IUPUI's first student run radio station), 3x Dean's List honoree and 2x Dean's List honorable mention

Chowan College

- Studies concentrated on Business Management
- Men's Varsity Basketball (NCAA Div. III)

SourceCon Indianapolis (2018-current) | Founding Director & Volunteer

This group is focused on sharing knowledge within the recruiting and sourcing industry. Secrets and competitive differences are put aside and a community of sharing and welcoming new ideas and insights develops.

- Develop, Coordinate, Market, and Emcee sourcing industry-based events for networking and education within the Indianapolis market.
- Successfully recruited a team of industry experts, supporters, and collaborators to help create and lead the Indy branch.

New Pal United Soccer Club (2017-Current)

Volunteer Coach for U6, U8, U10, and U12 age group soccer teams.